<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alex Zweber Leslie</title>
    <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alex Zweber Leslie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Alex Leslie</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 20:23:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azleslie.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dunbar and the Black Midwest Article in ALH</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/black-midwest-dunbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 20:23:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/black-midwest-dunbar/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to share, somewhat belatedly, that my article &amp;ldquo;Race, Region, and the Black Midwest in the Dunbar Decades&amp;rdquo; was published in this May&amp;rsquo;s American Literary History. If you click over to the Writing tab you&amp;rsquo;ll find a link to read the article. I hope you enjoy! On this page I&amp;rsquo;ll share a few brief thoughts on the process.
As with any publication, this one has a long history: it dates back to my third semester of graduate coursework, almost seven years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowell&#39;s A Fable for Critics Digital Edition</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/fable-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 20:23:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/fable-edition/</guid>
      <description>Over the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a digital edition of James Russell Lowell&amp;rsquo;s poem A Fable for Critics, the sensational 1848 satire of American literature from Poe to Emerson to Cooper. In both its colorful content and its lively reception, A Fable for Critics is a snapshot of the antebellum literary scene, with all its boisterous wit, youthful pretensions, cliquish bits, bitter feuds, and nagging uncertainty over whether there really was &amp;ndash; or could be &amp;ndash; a uniquely American literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Humanities Workshops</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/dh-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:54:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/dh-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Since the Spring 2018 semester I have served as the Digital Humanities Graduate Specialist for Rutgers Libraries. Over this time I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a number of workshops, from basic tutorials on using software popular among digital humanists (Gephi, Paladio, Tropy, etc.) to introductory and intermediate lessons on R programming in the humanities. The links each lead to a GitHub repository page, where you can find all the materials &amp;ndash; code, sample data, and step-by-step instructions &amp;ndash; for running the workshops on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo and GitHub Pages Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/hugo-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:20:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/hugo-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I used the static site generator Hugo and GitHub Pages hosting to build this website. Aside from one or two mistakes on my end, it was relatively easy to learn, customize, and deploy. That said, I did have to do some guessing and hopping between not-always-forthright tutorials.1 In the interests of learning more and helping others avoid my mistakes, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the whole process here from setup to deployment.2</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
