<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Zweber Leslie</title>
    <link>https://azleslie.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alex Zweber Leslie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Alex Leslie</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 20:23:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azleslie.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 12:45:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a scholar of American cultural history from the Early Republic to Modernism, with particular focus on circulation and reception, cultural geography, genre, and humanities data science. I received my PhD from the English Department at Rutgers University in 2021. I currently work as a Research Associate with the American Transportation Research Institute; I continue to use this site for active research in the fields of American literature and history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunbar and the Black Midwest Article in ALH</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/black-midwest-dunbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 20:23:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/black-midwest-dunbar/</guid>
      <description>I am pleased to share, somewhat belatedly, that my article &amp;ldquo;Race, Region, and the Black Midwest in the Dunbar Decades&amp;rdquo; was published in this May&amp;rsquo;s American Literary History. If you click over to the Writing tab you&amp;rsquo;ll find a link to read the article. I hope you enjoy! On this page I&amp;rsquo;ll share a few brief thoughts on the process.
As with any publication, this one has a long history: it dates back to my third semester of graduate coursework, almost seven years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bloomsday Tour of Every Episode in Joyce&#39;s Ulysses</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/bloomsday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 07:32:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/bloomsday/</guid>
      <description>Dublin is the heart of James Joyce&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece Ulysses, to such a degree that the day on which the novel takes place, June 16, has become a holiday known as &amp;ldquo;Bloomsday.&amp;rdquo; When I first visited the city in 2011, I wanted to do a one-day Ulysses walking tour by visiting a location from every episode in the novel. I was disappointed at the lack of guides online, so I assembled my own set of locations and optimal order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Costs of Book Production</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/marginal-costs-book-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 09:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/marginal-costs-book-production/</guid>
      <description>What did it cost to make a book? Books are complex commodities, the product of multiple distinct trades and industrial processes. Most literary scholarship makes frustratingly vague gestures at this question, so I decided to calculate an average production costs breakdown for the trade publishing industry in the opening decades of the twentieth century.1
Figure 1 shows the average expenses for each aspect of manufacturing and printing, drawn from book cost cards for novels in the J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter was for Reading</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/seasonal-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 02:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/seasonal-reading/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I wrote about seasonal and economic cycles in the publishing industry. This is a short addition on the relation between seasonal sales cycles and seasonal reading cycles.
Previously, I used data from the Stokes Company, a leading publisher of the early 20th century, to show how annual book sales peaked in the fall. From 1895 to 1902, 36% of Stokes&#39; sales occurred in October and November &amp;ndash; more than the seven months of January through July combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American Bookstores, 1915 &amp; 1925</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/booksellers1915/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 12:20:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/booksellers1915/</guid>
      <description>This dataset is a near-comprehensive record of bookstores and dedicated booksellers in the U.S. and Canada in 1915 and 1925, compiled by Publishers&#39; Weekly.1 Though Americans had several non-storefront sources of books (including mail order and subscription), this dataset gives insight into the locations, volume, and types of stores from which Americans could purchase books in the early 20th century.
The Publishers&#39; Weekly directories primarily consist of American booksellers, but they includes a significant number of Canadian booksellers as well as a few in Cuba, Mexico, and the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 12:45:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>You can download a PDF copy of my CV here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal and Economic Cycles in Publishing</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/publishing-cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 12:33:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/publishing-cycles/</guid>
      <description>Trade publishing &amp;ndash; general-interest books sold through retailers &amp;ndash; is a curious business. Narrative may be a necessity of life, but the book format as a commodity is not. Books have not been luxury items for the last hundred and fifty years: you could purchase them at department stores, drug stores, train stations, and news depots (so long as you weren&amp;rsquo;t too picky about what you were looking for). And yet, for the majority of consumers, books were not a regular purchase either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns and Predictability in Borrower Behavior</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/borrower-predictability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 09:11:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/borrower-predictability/</guid>
      <description>Readers are idiosyncratic. Recent work with library data has underscored this fact more than ever, but it has also drawn attention to specific patterns in reading behavior &amp;ndash; many even unexpected. What, then, is the relation between borrowing patterns and borrower idiosyncrasy at the broader level of overall library use: across many patrons’ full borrowing history?
I had the pleasure of presenting on this subject at the excellent Library Circulation Histories Workshop over the past couple weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowell&#39;s A Fable for Critics Digital Edition</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/fable-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 20:23:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/fable-edition/</guid>
      <description>Over the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a digital edition of James Russell Lowell&amp;rsquo;s poem A Fable for Critics, the sensational 1848 satire of American literature from Poe to Emerson to Cooper. In both its colorful content and its lively reception, A Fable for Critics is a snapshot of the antebellum literary scene, with all its boisterous wit, youthful pretensions, cliquish bits, bitter feuds, and nagging uncertainty over whether there really was &amp;ndash; or could be &amp;ndash; a uniquely American literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postbellum Newspaper Syndicates</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/newspaper-syndicates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 12:20:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/newspaper-syndicates/</guid>
      <description>This dataset represents the newspapers served by the five leading syndicates of the postbellum period. Syndicates fueled the rapid growth of the American press after the Civil War by providing cheap content &amp;ndash; not only news but literary entertainment, general information, and illustrations &amp;ndash; to fledgling editors and to newspapers in communities that otherwise would have been too small to sustain one. They exerted profound influence on the format itself and on what millions of Americans read, especially in rural areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howells Novels Ranking</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/howells-ranking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 20:36:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/howells-ranking/</guid>
      <description>American author William Dean Howells (1837-1920) wrote dozens of novels &amp;ndash; to say nothing of his equally influential editorial and critical output &amp;ndash; over a career whose longevity, acclaim, and broad dissemination can only really be compared today to that of (forgive me) someone like Stan Lee, Beyoncé, or the Simpsons. Consider: a reader of the four or five most recognized literary magazines from 1871 to 1890 would have encountered Howells&#39; fiction more months than not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Humanities Workshops</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/dh-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:54:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/dh-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Since the Spring 2018 semester I have served as the Digital Humanities Graduate Specialist for Rutgers Libraries. Over this time I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a number of workshops, from basic tutorials on using software popular among digital humanists (Gephi, Paladio, Tropy, etc.) to introductory and intermediate lessons on R programming in the humanities. The links each lead to a GitHub repository page, where you can find all the materials &amp;ndash; code, sample data, and step-by-step instructions &amp;ndash; for running the workshops on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newspaper Directory Advertiser Annotations</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/cook76-directory-annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 20:47:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/cook76-directory-annotations/</guid>
      <description>This is a small and unusual dataset, but it&amp;rsquo;s one that I like and learned a fair bit from: an advertiser&amp;rsquo;s annotations of a 1876 edition of C. A. Cook &amp;amp; Co.&amp;rsquo;s United States Newspaper Directory now held at the American Antiquarian Society.1
Newspaper agencies were a major go-between for advertisers and periodicals in the postbellum period, promising advertisers less hassle and publishers more reliable ad revenue streams. By the mid-1870s they published annual directories of the country&amp;rsquo;s newspapers, usually with a short record of political affiliation, genre, publisher, estimated circulation, and even short descriptions of the local population, all to help businesses choose where to place their ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Effects in Literary Monthlies</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/literary-monthlies-illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 09:21:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/literary-monthlies-illustrations/</guid>
      <description>Literary monthlies &amp;ndash; the Atlantic, Harper’s, the Century, Lippincott’s, and Scribner’s &amp;ndash; were some of the most widely read and highly respected magazines in nineteenth-century America. They don&amp;rsquo;t usually strike one as avant garde today, but I think that’s a misunderstanding for several reasons. For one, literary monthlies helped drive the development of new technologies and skills for reproducing illustrations. But they also expanded the possibilities of what illustrations could do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Spanish Flu Went Viral (And Then Got Boring)</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/spanish-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 19:19:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/spanish-flu/</guid>
      <description>What feels most modern about this pandemic &amp;ndash; the all-pervasive news coverage &amp;ndash; has a precedent in the 1918 Spanish flu that suggests why it’s already tapering.
Despite expert warnings that coronavirus repercussions will extend through summer, politicians aren’t the only ones wondering how much longer even partial lockdowns can last. The trouble isn’t just impatience. Almost two months after the cancellations of events and entertainment nationwide, the sheer inescapability of pandemic discourse raises the question of how much longer we can remain interested enough to follow its advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo and GitHub Pages Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/projects/hugo-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:20:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/projects/hugo-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I used the static site generator Hugo and GitHub Pages hosting to build this website. Aside from one or two mistakes on my end, it was relatively easy to learn, customize, and deploy. That said, I did have to do some guessing and hopping between not-always-forthright tutorials.1 In the interests of learning more and helping others avoid my mistakes, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the whole process here from setup to deployment.2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News Rhythms</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/news-rhythms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:34:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/news-rhythms/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re quite familiar today with the idea of news cycles: the fluctuating window of time it takes for a full turnover of major news items. Underlying these variable, context-driven cycles are other, structural patterns of news making and circulating. These are what I like to call news rhythms.
The difference is partly a classic superstructure / base distinction in that many of the factors contributing to news rhythms are economic or industrial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 20:44:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Re-Writing and Re-Fighting the Civil War (358:442, Summer 2018; Syllabus)
As recent conflicts over Confederate monuments have shown, the American Civil War remains hotly contested over one hundred and fifty years after its conclusion: why did it begin? what did soldiers or politicians on either side fight for? what was the result? who really “won”? If even such fundamental questions as these seem unclear to so many people, it’s because the story of the Civil War has been retold so many times and for so many different reasons that the war itself has become less important than the stories we tell about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 20:44:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/writing/</guid>
      <description>Peer Reviewed &amp;ldquo;Race, Region, and the Black Midwest in the Dunbar Decades,&amp;rdquo; American Literary History 34.2 (Summer 2022). Download here.
In this essay I show how Paul Laurence Dunbar, today most associated with plantation poetry, successfully utilized Midwestern identity as an alternative site for Black expression and cultural affiliation. Writing in Midwestern dialects and tropes, Dunbar was able to become widely recognized as a Midwestern writer and in doing so compel white readers to place regional belonging over racial alterity as a framework for interpreting cultural difference even at the height of Jim Crow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antebellum Periodicals Metadata</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/antebellum-periodicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 20:09:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/antebellum-periodicals/</guid>
      <description>This is a CSV file of the basic metadata for the American Antiquarian Society&amp;rsquo;s Historical Periodicals Collection from 1821-1865, drawn from the EBSCO coverage lists.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made several improvements. First, I added geographic coordinates for publishing locations. Second, I eliminated some of the redundancy from the original files, though some remains. I wish that the genre field were more consistent and more consolidated, but I think the only way to do that would be to go through entry by entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 19:45:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/new-site/</guid>
      <description>I decided to bite the bullet and make a website. I hope you like it.
You&amp;rsquo;ll find various professional materials collected here, complete with links and downloads. I also hope to use this site as a place to make available some of the datasets from my research and to share occasional thoughts on whatever materials or methods happen to excite me at the moment.
As for the site itself, I wanted something that was minimalist in both aesthetics and organization in order to keep content local, get under the hood, and get more experience with HTML, CSS, and the command line along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
