<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Alex Zweber Leslie</title>
    <link>https://azleslie.com/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Alex Zweber Leslie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Alex Leslie</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 12:20:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azleslie.com/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>North American Bookstores, 1915 &amp; 1925</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/booksellers1915/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 12:20:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/booksellers1915/</guid>
      <description>This dataset is a near-comprehensive record of bookstores and dedicated booksellers in the U.S. and Canada in 1915 and 1925, compiled by Publishers&#39; Weekly.1 Though Americans had several non-storefront sources of books (including mail order and subscription), this dataset gives insight into the locations, volume, and types of stores from which Americans could purchase books in the early 20th century.
The Publishers&#39; Weekly directories primarily consist of American booksellers, but they includes a significant number of Canadian booksellers as well as a few in Cuba, Mexico, and the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postbellum Newspaper Syndicates</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/newspaper-syndicates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 12:20:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/newspaper-syndicates/</guid>
      <description>This dataset represents the newspapers served by the five leading syndicates of the postbellum period. Syndicates fueled the rapid growth of the American press after the Civil War by providing cheap content &amp;ndash; not only news but literary entertainment, general information, and illustrations &amp;ndash; to fledgling editors and to newspapers in communities that otherwise would have been too small to sustain one. They exerted profound influence on the format itself and on what millions of Americans read, especially in rural areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newspaper Directory Advertiser Annotations</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/cook76-directory-annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 20:47:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/cook76-directory-annotations/</guid>
      <description>This is a small and unusual dataset, but it&amp;rsquo;s one that I like and learned a fair bit from: an advertiser&amp;rsquo;s annotations of a 1876 edition of C. A. Cook &amp;amp; Co.&amp;rsquo;s United States Newspaper Directory now held at the American Antiquarian Society.1
Newspaper agencies were a major go-between for advertisers and periodicals in the postbellum period, promising advertisers less hassle and publishers more reliable ad revenue streams. By the mid-1870s they published annual directories of the country&amp;rsquo;s newspapers, usually with a short record of political affiliation, genre, publisher, estimated circulation, and even short descriptions of the local population, all to help businesses choose where to place their ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antebellum Periodicals Metadata</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/data/antebellum-periodicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 20:09:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/data/antebellum-periodicals/</guid>
      <description>This is a CSV file of the basic metadata for the American Antiquarian Society&amp;rsquo;s Historical Periodicals Collection from 1821-1865, drawn from the EBSCO coverage lists.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made several improvements. First, I added geographic coordinates for publishing locations. Second, I eliminated some of the redundancy from the original files, though some remains. I wish that the genre field were more consistent and more consolidated, but I think the only way to do that would be to go through entry by entry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
