<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alex Zweber Leslie</title>
    <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alex Zweber Leslie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2023 Alex Leslie</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:32:13 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azleslie.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The End of the Gift Market in Books?</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/end-of-the-book-gift-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/end-of-the-book-gift-market/</guid>
      <description>The gift market was one of the most defining features of the book publishing industry for over 150 years. Ever since the book became an accessible commodity, consumers have purchased them for others around the major holidays: in America historically, chiefly Christmas and to a lesser extent Easter. This gift function was so concentrated in a single season &amp;ndash; the lead-up to Christmas &amp;ndash; and represented such a large percentage of total annual sales that for much of the 19th century the book could be considered foremost a gift commodity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zola Recommended Reading Orders</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/zola-reading-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 14:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/zola-reading-order/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I posted my ranking of Emile Zola&amp;rsquo;s Rougon-Maquart novels. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked about reading order, a frequent Zola question. Though they all deal with individuals from the same extended family, the novels are self-contained and can be read (or not read) in any order. Yet some order can enhance the experience of reading Les Rougon-Macquart, whether one novel or twenty.
There is of course the original publication order, which offers historical interest but is otherwise somewhat arbitrary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zola Novel Ranking</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/zola-novel-ranking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 14:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/zola-novel-ranking/</guid>
      <description>Émile Zola is without doubt one of the ten or so most influential novelists to have ever lived. His twenty loosely-connected Rougon-Maquart novels – depicting French gilded age society from its most elite echelons to its most abject slums – was a critical and popular lightning rod, a pivotal influence in at least four continents and a dozen language traditions.1 While Germinal and Nana remain recognized masterpieces, many others are great as well; yet few people read the entire sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dedicated Bookstore Predicament</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/bookseller-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 09:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/bookseller-types/</guid>
      <description>A lot of ink has been spilled over the decline of the dedicated bookstore &amp;ndash; stores dedicated &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; or primarily to selling books &amp;ndash; amid the rise of online retailers and e-readers in the 21st century. Yet dedicated bookstores were often not the main source of books in the U.S. historically. In fact, that market role was highly contested over the last two centuries.
In the early 20th century, a consumer could buy books from many different types of retailer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Newsprint Vocabulary Size</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/rural-newsprint-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 08:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/rural-newsprint-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>I saw a recent tweet by Richard Dawkins repeat a silly anecdote that 19th century peasants had an average vocabulary of only 250 words. There are many ways to disprove this obvious falsehood.1 One way would be to look at linguistic materials that a particular demographic used. Newspapers were a key source of information and communication in the 19th century: they included a wide variety of content &amp;ndash; news, ads, entertainment, correspondence, domestic tips, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bloomsday Tour of Every Episode in Joyce&#39;s Ulysses</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/bloomsday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 07:32:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/bloomsday/</guid>
      <description>Dublin is the heart of James Joyce&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece Ulysses, to such a degree that the day on which the novel takes place, June 16, has become a holiday known as &amp;ldquo;Bloomsday.&amp;rdquo; When I first visited the city in 2011, I wanted to do a one-day Ulysses walking tour by visiting a location from every episode in the novel. I was disappointed at the lack of guides online, so I assembled my own set of locations and optimal order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Costs of Book Production</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/marginal-costs-book-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 09:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/marginal-costs-book-production/</guid>
      <description>What did it cost to make a book? Books are complex commodities, the product of multiple distinct trades and industrial processes. Most literary scholarship makes frustratingly vague gestures at this question, so I decided to calculate an average production costs breakdown for the trade publishing industry in the opening decades of the twentieth century.1
Figure 1 shows the average expenses for each aspect of manufacturing and printing, drawn from book cost cards for novels in the J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter was for Reading</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/seasonal-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 02:32:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/seasonal-reading/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I wrote about seasonal and economic cycles in the publishing industry. This is a short addition on the relation between seasonal sales cycles and seasonal reading cycles.
Previously, I used data from the Stokes Company, a leading publisher of the early 20th century, to show how annual book sales peaked in the fall. From 1895 to 1902, 36% of Stokes&#39; sales occurred in October and November &amp;ndash; more than the seven months of January through July combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal and Economic Cycles in Publishing</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/publishing-cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 12:33:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/publishing-cycles/</guid>
      <description>Trade publishing &amp;ndash; general-interest books sold through retailers &amp;ndash; is a curious business. Narrative may be a necessity of life, but the book format as a commodity is not. Books have not been luxury items for the last hundred and fifty years: you could purchase them at department stores, drug stores, train stations, and news depots (so long as you weren&amp;rsquo;t too picky about what you were looking for). And yet, for the majority of consumers, books were not a regular purchase either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns and Predictability in Borrower Behavior</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/borrower-predictability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 09:11:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/borrower-predictability/</guid>
      <description>Readers are idiosyncratic. Recent work with library data has underscored this fact more than ever, but it has also drawn attention to specific patterns in reading behavior &amp;ndash; many even unexpected. What, then, is the relation between borrowing patterns and borrower idiosyncrasy at the broader level of overall library use: across many patrons’ full borrowing history?
I had the pleasure of presenting on this subject at the excellent Library Circulation Histories Workshop over the past couple weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howells Novels Ranking</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/howells-ranking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 20:36:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/howells-ranking/</guid>
      <description>American author William Dean Howells (1837-1920) wrote dozens of novels &amp;ndash; to say nothing of his equally influential editorial and critical output &amp;ndash; over a career whose longevity, acclaim, and broad dissemination can only really be compared today to that of (forgive me) someone like Stan Lee, Beyoncé, or the Simpsons. Consider: a reader of the four or five most recognized literary magazines from 1871 to 1890 would have encountered Howells&#39; fiction more months than not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Effects in Literary Monthlies</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/literary-monthlies-illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 09:21:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/literary-monthlies-illustrations/</guid>
      <description>Literary monthlies &amp;ndash; the Atlantic, Harper’s, the Century, Lippincott’s, and Scribner’s &amp;ndash; were some of the most widely read and highly respected magazines in nineteenth-century America. They don&amp;rsquo;t usually strike one as avant garde today, but I think that’s a misunderstanding for several reasons. For one, literary monthlies helped drive the development of new technologies and skills for reproducing illustrations. But they also expanded the possibilities of what illustrations could do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Spanish Flu Went Viral (And Then Got Boring)</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/spanish-flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 19:19:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/spanish-flu/</guid>
      <description>What feels most modern about this pandemic &amp;ndash; the all-pervasive news coverage &amp;ndash; has a precedent in the 1918 Spanish flu that suggests why it’s already tapering.
Despite expert warnings that coronavirus repercussions will extend through summer, politicians aren’t the only ones wondering how much longer even partial lockdowns can last. The trouble isn’t just impatience. Almost two months after the cancellations of events and entertainment nationwide, the sheer inescapability of pandemic discourse raises the question of how much longer we can remain interested enough to follow its advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News Rhythms</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/news-rhythms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 13:34:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/news-rhythms/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re quite familiar today with the idea of news cycles: the fluctuating window of time it takes for a full turnover of major news items. Underlying these variable, context-driven cycles are other, structural patterns of news making and circulating. These are what I like to call news rhythms.
The difference is partly a classic superstructure / base distinction in that many of the factors contributing to news rhythms are economic or industrial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site</title>
      <link>https://azleslie.com/posts/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 19:45:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azleslie.com/posts/new-site/</guid>
      <description>I decided to bite the bullet and make a website. I hope you like it.
You&amp;rsquo;ll find various professional materials collected here, complete with links and downloads. I also hope to use this site as a place to make available some of the datasets from my research and to share occasional thoughts on whatever materials or methods happen to excite me at the moment.
As for the site itself, I wanted something that was minimalist in both aesthetics and organization in order to keep content local, get under the hood, and get more experience with HTML, CSS, and the command line along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
